Brendan Cheong Ern Jie

+6594569855 | Singapore | brendancej1@gmail.com

github.com/BrendanCheong | linkedin.com/in/brendan-cheong-ern-jie | Available for May - Aug/Nov Internships

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a self-driven, independent learner who picked up programming in the midst of my Economics degree, and never looked back. In the last three years of my undergraduate degree, I completed a second major in Business Analytics, learnt multiple mainstream programming languages and frameworks, completed multiple software engineering internships and personal coding projects. I hope to pursue a fulfilling career as a Software Engineer building impactful products.

EDUCATION

B.Soc.Sci in Economics, Second Major in Business Analytics

National University of Singapore

Aug 2020 — May 2024

- Business Analytics GPA (10 Courses): 4.00/5.00
- Relevant Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Object Oriented Programming Principles, Database Management Systems, Web Development, Interaction Design

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intern

Solar AI Technologies

May 2022 — Aug 2022 Singapore

- Built and launched a new customer portal, which allows over 100 customers to manage their solar installation and liaise with solar panel installers.
- Developed high-performance serverless GraphQL APIs in Typescript backed by ElasticSearch and DynamoDB to provide consistent data flow for the business and customer portal.
- Worked with the sales team to build an internal Customer Relationship Management (CRM) web application to manage over 200 customers contracts, which doubled their productivity.
- Tech stack: React.js, Typescript, Next.js, GraphQL, Elasticsearch, Amazon Web Services (AWS): DynamoDB, S3

Robotic Process Automation Intern

Ministry of Communications and Information

Dec 2021 — Apr 2022

Singapore

- Built an internal automated bot to register over 500 staff members for Zoom meetings every week.
- Created automated email scripts using Python to remind staff members of meetings, reducing the time taken to send emails manually by 50%.
- Tech stack: Python, VB.Net, UiPath

SKILLS

Programming Languages Technologies (Proficient): Typescript, Javascript, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS (Familiar): Python, Java React.js, Redux, Next.js, AWS, GraphQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL

PROJECTS

Build.me: Price Aggregating Web application

github.com/BrendanCheong/Build.me

- Co-developed a full-stack web application that allows users to compare the performance of different computer builds.
- Aggregated over 500 products with price points for easy price comparisons and reduced search time for finding computer parts by 30 minutes.
- Tech stack: React.js, Express.js, MongoDB, TailwindCSS, Node.js

Lights & Locks: Stock Management Desktop Application

github.com/BrendanCheong/Lights-And-Locks

- Led a team of 5 to develop a full-stack desktop application that allows users to purchase, search and send smart lights & locks for servicing as part of a software development class.
- Tech stack: Python, Flask, PyQT5, MySQL, MongoDB,